<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>All Elder Meetings</title>
    <description>All Elder Meeting archives of audio recordings, PDFs and notes. 
</description>
    <link>http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 08:29:14 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2016 08:29:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pastor Vernon&#39;s Elder Prayer</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Prayer is something deeper than words. It is present in the soul before it has
been formulated into words. And it abides in the soul after the last words of
prayer have passed over our lips.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;— O. Hallesby (1879-1961), Prayer,
London: Inter-Varsity Fellowship, 1943, reprint, Augsburg Fortress Books, 1975,
1994, p. 16&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
Can we believe that God ever modifies His action in response to the
suggestions of man? For infinite wisdom does not need telling what is best,
and infinite goodness needs no urging to do it. But neither does God need
any of those things that are done by finite agents, whether living or
inanimate.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
He could, if He chose, repair our bodies miraculously without food; or give
us food without the aid of farmers, bakers, and butchers; or knowledge
without the aid of learned men; or convert the heathen without
missionaries.
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Instead, He allows soils and weather and animals and the muscles, minds,
and wills of men to cooperate in the execution of His will. &quot;God&quot;, says
Pascal, &quot;instituted prayer in order to lend to His creatures the dignity of
causality.&quot;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;— C. S. Lewis (1898-1963), &quot;The Efficacy of Prayer&quot;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for refugees, orphans, widows and the peoples
of the world who are facing shortages of food, water, clean air,
shelter, energy and medicine, that you would provide for them
in their needs.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The earth is the Lord’s and all it contains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for the parts of the earth that are under severe
stress - from civil war in Syria to floods in Louisiana and Texas,
from continuing war in Afghanistan to teenage deaths in
Ocoee.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The earth is the Lord’s and all it contains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for “all in authority” (1 Timothy 2:2), that they would
seek ways of peace and not of war, that they would grant and
promote religious liberty, conservation of resources, and free
enterprise. We pray for “spiritual statesmen,” that they be granted
courage and wisdom to speak biblical truth and apply gospel
principles to correct the wrongs in the world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The earth is the Lord’s and all it contains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for God-fearing, wise, just and compassionate rulers at
every level, that they would honor you in their work, that they would
protect earth, air, water, public health and manage resources. We
pray for those seeking office - particularly the highest office in our
land that they would lead with wisdom and humility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The Earth is the Lord’s and all it contains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for all living in closed and persecuted
nations, that you grant protection, bring revelation of Jesus
Christ as Messiah; send forth your light and gospel truth—
let it break in upon them.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We pray for all living in religious systems of idolatry, that
you deliver them from inherited deities and idols; instruct
and help them learn to worship and walk in the ways of the
Living God.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The Earth is the Lord’s and all it contains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We pray for unity in the Church in the U.S. and around the
world, that the prayers of Jesus in John 17 be answered and
realized in our day; help each of us and all Christians practice love
in diversity.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We pray for Revival and an outpouring of the Holy Spirit, that
kingdom peacemakers be called and released who humbly hold to
unity in the body of Christ in their hearts, minds and ministries.
We take a personal posture and pray against divisiveness, envy,
pride, deceit, personal ambition, contempt, anger, slander,
covetousness, and immoral and reckless folly in the body of Christ.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The Earth is the Lord’s and all it contains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WE PRAY FOR NORTHLAND CHURCH.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pray for our purpose to bring people to maturity in Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pray for our vision to see people coming to Christ, and to be
transformed together as we link locally and globally to worship
and serve everywhere, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pray for our mission to respond to Your grace and goodness
in how we worship You, read the Bible, share our stories, be in
community, pray, serve others and live generously. We believe as
we respond together to You we will be transformed into the
image of Christ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One: We humbly offer ourselves and pray that we might be a people set apart for
your purposes—to the poor and suffering, to all who do not yet know you, to all
across our land and in the entire world.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We pray that our hearts will be open to wisdom and to your ways, that you will
grant us grace to partner in protecting the life and health of the unborn and of all
living, in stewarding and protecting your creation, and in caring for and loving
those deemed to be “the least.” (Matthew 24:40)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We pray that you will do a mighty work in our midst, that you will fashion us to be
a faithful people, a collaborative community of the Redeemed, who praise you in
all circumstances, and who rejoice together in the good works you have prepared
in advance for us to accomplish. (Ephesians 2:10)
— For the glory of God alone.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All: The Earth is the Lord’s and all it contains. Amen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download: &lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/nacd_assets/eldermeetings/ElderPrayer-3-16-16.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;material-icons&quot;&gt;picture_as_pdf&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2016/03/Elder-Prayer</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2016/03/Elder-Prayer</guid>
        
        
        <category>pdf</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Study the Bible</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pastor Dan teaches on how to study the Bible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/nacd_assets/eldermeetings/20160120-Dan-Bible-Study.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-study-the-bible-outline&quot;&gt;How to Study the Bible Outline&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number one factor in growth in Christ likeness is Bible engagement.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Word of God has a power all its own:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the beginning God spoke and His word produced out of nothing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Isaiah tells us God’s Word will not return void but do what He intends it to do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is compared to a two edged sword that cuts between bone and marrow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jesus was the Word made flesh and He came in power. To become more like Him we must know the Word.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paul urged that we be diligent workman who can rightly handle the Word of Truth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;basic-rules&quot;&gt;Basic Rules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scripture must interpret Scripture&lt;/strong&gt;, Jesus does this example discussion on divorce and His use of Genesis 2:24&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Didactic must shed light on Narrative&lt;/strong&gt;, Acts compared to 1 Corinthians 12&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The more clear must inform the less clear&lt;/strong&gt;, All scripture is God breathed so it is not in conflict with itself. If we don’t understand a passage or think it conflicts with something that is clear, then we need to rethink in light of the clear passage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It should lead to Christ and the Gospel&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;John 5:39 – Jesus said that the Pharisees search the scriptures and so they should have received Him because the scriptures point to Him.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;We can get lost in the minutia and never get to Jesus, i.e. Study the tabernacle in the Old Testament and never see that the purpose is to point to Jesus who according to John 1 came and dwelt, literally tabernacled or pitched His tent, among us. Be sure to look for the overarching teaching of redemption, the Gospel, the Messiah and our human need for grace.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bible is just like and completely unlike every other book.&lt;/strong&gt; So the rules of studying literature are the same, yet the power of the Bible makes it unique.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most Important: The Holy Spirit must be consulted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;context-is-crucial--it-is-the-most-often-overlooked-and-yet-the-easiest-to-correct&quot;&gt;Context is Crucial – it is the most often overlooked and yet the easiest to correct.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immediate&lt;/strong&gt; - Ephesians 5:21-6:9 You cannot divorce verse 21 from 22 and you can’t stop at the end of chapter 5.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Book&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Especially in historical books, what has already happened?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Even in other books example – Paul’s letters have a context in terms of who they were written to and what the culture was.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bible&lt;/strong&gt; - Where in the Bible does it fall?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;genre-matters&quot;&gt;Genre Matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We read narratives differently from poetry and from proverbs or prophecy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;questions-to-ask&quot;&gt;Questions to Ask:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Observation – What do we see in the text?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interpretation – What does it mean?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Application – How should it change the way I follow Jesus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ways-to-study&quot;&gt;Ways to study&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master a book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Topical.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Word.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2016/01/Bible-Study-with-Dan</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2016/01/Bible-Study-with-Dan</guid>
        
        
        <category>pdf</category>
        
        <category>audio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sabbatical Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pastor Joel shares six points from his sabbatical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/nacd_assets/eldermeetings/sixpoints.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2015/08/Sabbatical-Report</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2015/08/Sabbatical-Report</guid>
        
        
        <category>report</category>
        
        <category>audio</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dechurched Discussion</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Chad Turnbull leads our group of Elders through recent trends on the dechurched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audio&quot;&gt;Audio&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/nacd_assets/eldermeetings/dechurched.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;slides&quot;&gt;Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://s3.amazonaws.com/nacd_assets/eldermeetings/ChurchTrends.pdf&quot;&gt;Church Trends&lt;/a&gt; by Chad Turnbull&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2015/08/Dechurched</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://eldermeetings.northlandchurch.net/2015/08/Dechurched</guid>
        
        
        <category>decurched</category>
        
        <category>pdf</category>
        
        <category>audio</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
